## **Guoyang Xie**

# Homepage: <a href="https://guoyang-xie.github.io">https://guoyang-xie.github.io</a>

#### **SHORT BIO**

I am Guoyang Xie, and I will achieve my machine learning PhD degree at the University of Surrey on October 16th, 2023. My research topic is **Deep Learning-based Image Anomaly Detection in Industrial Manufacturing and Medical Imaging.** I have 13 papers published in top conferences and journals, including NeurIPS, ICLR, ACM MM, ACM Computing, and TCYB. Prior to that, I worked at the GAC Research Institute and Baidu, developing algorithms for autonomous driving perception.

#### **EDUCATION**

- University of Surrey, Machine Learning PhD, 2019.10-2023.10, Supervisor: Yaochu Jin (IEEE Fellow, Humboldt Professor for AI, a Member of Academia Europaea)
- 2. Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, MPhil(Major:Robotics), 2013.09-2015.09, Supervisor: Ming Liu
- 3. University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Bachelor(Electronic Engineering), 2009.9-2013.06

#### **PUBLICATION**

- 1. **Guoyang Xie\***, Jinbao Wang\*, Jiaqi Liu, Yaochu Jin and Feng Zheng, "Pushing the Limits of Few Shot Anomaly Detection in Industry Vision: Graphcore", (ICLR 2023)
- 2. Jiaqi Liu\*, **Guoyang Xie\***, Ruitao Chen\*, Xinpeng Li, Jinbao Wang, Yong Liu, and Feng Zheng, "Real3D-AD: A Dataset of Point Cloud Anomaly Detection", (NeurIPS Dataset and Benchmark Track)
- 3. Ruitao Chen\*, **Guoyang Xie**\*, Jiaqi Liu\*, Jinbao Wang, Ziqi Luo, Jinfan Wang and Feng Zheng, "EasyNet: An Easy Network for 3D Industrial Anomaly Detection", (ACM MM)
- 4. **Guoyang Xie\***, Jinbao Wang\*, Jiaqi Liu\*, Jiayi Lyu, Yong Liu, Chengjie Wang, Feng Zheng, and Yaochu Jin, "IM-IAD: Industrial Image Anomaly Detection Benchmark in Manufacturing", (TCYB, IF: 19.217, Minor Revision)
- 5. L.Zhang, S.Zhang, **Guoyang Xie**, Jiaqi Liu, Hua Yan, Jinbao Wang, and Feng Zheng, "What makes a good data augmentation for few-shot unsupervised image anomaly detection", (CVPR Workshop 2023)
- 6. Jinbao Wang\*, **Guoyang Xie**\*, Yawen Huang\*, Yefeng Zheng, Yaochu Jin and Feng Zheng, "FedMed-ATL: Misaligned Unpaired Cross-Modality Neuroimage Synthesis via Transform Loss", (ACM MM 2023)

- 7. **Guoyang Xie**, Tao Xu, Carsten Isert, Michael Aeberhard, Shaohua Li and M.Liu, "Online Active Calibration for a Multi-LRF System", (ITSC 2015)
- 8. **Guoyang Xie\*,** Yawen Huang\*, Jinbao Wang, Jiayi Lyu, Feng Zheng, Yefeng Zheng, and Yaochu Jin, "Cross-Modality Neuroimage Synthesis: A Survey", (ACM Computing Surveys 2023, IF: 14.324)
- 9. **Guoyang Xie\***, Jinbao Wang, Guo Yu, Feng Zheng and Yaochu Jin, "Tiny Adversarial Multi-Objective One-Shot Neural Architecture Search", (CAIS, IF: 6.72)
- 10. Jinbao Wang\*, **Guoyang Xie**\*, Yawen Huang\*, Jiayi Lyu, Feng Zheng, Yefeng Zheng and Yaochu Jin, "FedMed-GAN: Federated Domain Translation on Unsupervised Cross-Modality Brain Image Synthesis", (NeuroComputing, IF: 5.719)
- 11. Jiaqi Liu\*, **Guoyang Xie**\*, Jinbao Wang\*, Shangnian Li, Chengjie Wang, Feng Zheng, and Yaochu Jin, "Deep Industrial Image Anomaly Detection: A Survey", (Machine Learning Research, 2023)
- 12. Jinbao Wang\*, **Guoyang Xie**\*, Yawen Huang\*, Jiayi Lyu, Feng Zheng, Yefeng Zheng, and Yaochu Jin, "K-CROSS: K-Space Aware Cross-Modality Score for Synthesized Neuroimage Quality Assessment, (Submitted to JBHI)
- 13. **Guoyang Xie\***, Jiaqi Liu\*, Jinbao Wang, Yaochu Jin, and Feng Zheng, "Transfer-AD: Transferable Image Anomaly Detection in Changeover Procedure", (Submitted to AAAI 2023)
- 14. Jiang Xi\*, **Guoyang Xie**\*, Jinbao Wang\*, Yong Liu, Chengjie Wang, Feng Zheng, Yaochu Jin, "A Survey of Visual Sensory Anomaly", arXiv preprint arXiv:2202.07006

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

PRINCIPLE PERCEPTION ALGORITHM ENGINEER - 2017.12-2019.9

- 1. Build a comprehensive perception benchmark for L3 and L4 Level Autonomous Driving, including:
  - Highway lane detection benchmark
  - Free-space semantic segmentation benchmark
  - Highway object-detection benchmark
- 2. Intelligent Parking-Assist Algorithm, including:
  - Visual simultaneous localization and mapping algorithm
  - Visual object detection algorithm
- 3. Build a large-scale dataset for L3/L4 autonomous driving tasks, including:
  - Highway semantic segmentation
  - Real-time object detection

- 1. Deep Learning-based 3D object detection
  - Random forest tree-based 3D object classification
  - End-to-end 3D point cloud object detection, classification and tracking

#### **SERVICE**

- 2020-2023, CAIS Reviewer
- 2022, AAAI Reviewer
- 2023, NeurIPS Reviewer
- 2023, TEVC Reviewer
- 2023, ACM MM Reviewer
- 2023, ICLR Reviewer
- 2023, TETCI Reviewer
- 2023, TNNLS Reviewer

#### **SKILLS**

Programming Language: Python, Latex, Matlab

Language: Cantonese, Mandarin, English

### GITHUB REPOS(代码库)

- Open-IAD: https://github.com/M-3LAB/open-iad
- FedMed-GAN: https://github.com/M-3LAB/FedMed-GAN
- Awesome Industrial Image Anomaly Detection: https://github.com/M-3LAB/ awesome-industrial-anomaly-detection
- Brain-GAN Survey: https://github.com/M-3LAB/awesome-multimodal-brain-image-systhesis